Daniel Seita

seita@usc.edu https://danielseita.github.io Last Updated: December 14, 2023.

EMPLOYMENT (SINCE PHD)

Assistant Professor

August 2023 — Present

University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA

• I am a tenure-track Assistant Professor with standard research, teaching, advising, and service duties.

Post-Doc Carnegie Mellon University Sept 2021 — July 2023 Pittsburgh, PA

 Advised by Prof. David Held in the Robotics Institute, specializing on algorithms and learning for robot manipulation of deformable objects. Duties also include mentoring students, some teaching, and assisting with grant writing.

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley. PhD, Computer Science. GPA: 3.90/4.00 Advised by John Canny and Ken Goldberg.

Awarded 2021

Williams College. BA, Computer Science and Mathematics (double major), GPA: 3.90/4.00

Awarded 2014

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are in robotics, computer vision, and machine learning, with a focus on robot manipulation of diverse, complex, and deformable objects. I am interested in learning novel and/or multimodal observation and action representations that can lead to more sample-efficient and reliable learning, and which I hope will advance robot manipulation.

Publications (Conferences and Journals)

A list of these publications is also available on my Google Scholar page. Asterisks (*) indicate equal first authorship, daggers (†) indicate equal non-first authorship.

- Chen, L. Y., Shi, B., Lin, R., Seita, D., Ahmad, A., Cheng, R., Kollar, T., Held, D. & Goldberg, K. Bagging by Learning to Singulate Layers Using Interactive Perception. IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) (2023).
- 2. Chen, L. Y., Shi, B., Seita, D., Cheng, R., Kollar, T., Held, D. & Goldberg, K. AutoBag: Learning to Open Plastic Bags and Insert Objects. IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) (2023).
- Seita, D., Wang[†], Y., Shetty[†], S. J., Li[†], E. Y., Erickson, Z. & Held, D. ToolFlowNet: Robotic Manipulation with Tools via Predicting Tool Flow from Point Clouds. Conference on Robot Learning (CoRL) (2022).
- Tirumala*, S., Weng*, T., Seita*, D., Kroemer, O., Temel, Z. & Held, D. Learning to Singulate Layers of Cloth using Tactile Feedback. IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) (2022).
- 5. Chen*, L. Y., Huang*, H., Novoseller, E., Seita, D., Ichnowski, J., Laskey, M., Cheng, R., Kollar, T. & Goldberg, K. Efficiently Learning Single-Arm Fling Motions to Smooth Garments. International Symposium on Robotics Research (ISRR) (2022).
- 6. Hwang, M., Ichnowski, J., Thananjeyan, B., Seita, D., Paradis, S., Fer, D., Low, T. & Goldberg, K. Automating Surgical Peg Transfer: Calibration with Deep Learning Can Exceed Speed, Accuracy, and Consistency of Humans. IEEE Transactions on Automation Science and Engineering (TASE) (2022).
- Lim*, V., Huang*, H., Chen, Y., Wang, J., Ichnowski, J., Seita, D., Laskey, M. & Goldberg, K. Planar Robot Casting with Real2Sim2Real Self-Supervised Learning. IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) (2022).
- 8. Hoque*, R., Seita*, D., Balakrishna, A., Ganapathi, A., Tanwani, A., Jamali, N., Yamane, K., Iba, S. & Goldberg, K. VisuoSpatial Foresight for Physical Sequential Fabric Manipulation. Autonomous Robots (AURO) (2021).
- 9. Hoque, R., Balakrishna, A., Putterman, C., Luo, M., Brown, D. S., Seita, D., Thananjeyan, B., Novoseller, E. & Goldberg, K. LazyDAgger: Reducing Context Switching in Interactive Imitation Learning. IEEE Conference on Automation Science and Engineering (CASE) (2021).

- 10. **Seita**, **D.**, Florence, P., Tompson, J., Coumans, E., Sindhwani, V., Goldberg, K. & Zeng, A. Learning to Rearrange Deformable Cables, Fabrics, and Bags with Goal-Conditioned Transporter Networks. *IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)* (2021).
- 11. Zhang, H., Ichnowski, J., **Seita**, **D.**, Wang, J., Huang, H. & Goldberg, K. Robots of the Lost Arc: Self-Supervised Learning to Dynamically Manipulate Fixed-Endpoint Cables. *IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)* (2021).
- 12. Ganapathi, A., Sundaresan, P., Thananjeyan, B., Balakrishna, A., **Seita**, **D.**, Grannen, J., Hwang, M., Hoque, R., Gonzalez, J., Jamali, N., Yamane, K., Iba, S. & Goldberg, K. Learning Dense Visual Correspondences in Simulation to Smooth and Fold Real Fabrics. *IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)* (2021).
- 13. Paradis, S., Hwang, M., Thananjeyan, B., Ichnowski, J., **Seita**, **D.**, Fer, D., Low, T., Gonzalez, J. E. & Goldberg, K. Intermittent Visual Servoing: Efficiently Learning Policies Robust to Instrument Changes for High-precision Surgical Manipulation. *IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)* (2021).
- 14. **Seita**, **D.**, Ganapathi, A., Hoque, R., Hwang, M., Cen, E., Tanwani, A. K., Balakrishna, A., Thananjeyan, B., Ichnowski, J., Jamali, N., Yamane, K., Iba, S., Canny, J. & Goldberg, K. Deep Imitation Learning of Sequential Fabric Smoothing From an Algorithmic Supervisor. *IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)* (2020).
- 15. Hwang, M., Thananjeyan, B., Paradis, S., **Seita**, **D.**, Ichnowski, J., Fer, D., Low, T. & Goldberg, K. Efficiently Calibrating Cable-Driven Surgical Robots with RGBD Fiducial Sensing and Recurrent Neural Networks. *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)* (2020).
- 16. Hoque*, R., **Seita***, **D.**, Balakrishna, A., Ganapathi, A., Tanwani, A., Jamali, N., Yamane, K., Iba, S. & Goldberg, K. VisuoSpatial Foresight for Multi-Step, Multi-Task Fabric Manipulation. *Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)* (2020).
- 17. Hwang*, M., **Seita***, **D.**, Thananjeyan, B., Ichnowski, J., Paradis, S., Fer, D., Low, T. & Goldberg, K. Applying Depth-Sensing to Automated Surgical Manipulation with a da Vinci Robot. *International Symposium on Medical Robotics (ISMR)* (2020).
- 18. **Seita***, **D.**, Jamali*, N., Laskey*, M., Berenstein, R., Tanwani, A. K., Baskaran, P., Iba, S., Canny, J. & Goldberg, K. Deep Transfer Learning of Pick Points on Fabric for Robot Bed-Making. *International Symposium on Robotics Research (ISRR)* (2019).
- 19. Pan, X., **Seita**, **D.**, Gao, Y. & Canny, J. Risk Averse Robust Adversarial Reinforcement Learning. *IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)* (2019).
- 20. **Seita**, **D.**, Krishnan, S., Fox, R., McKinley, S., Canny, J. & Goldberg, K. Fast and Reliable Autonomous Surgical Debridement with Cable-Driven Robots Using a Two-Phase Calibration Procedure. *IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)* (2018).
- 21. **Seita**, **D.**, Pan, X., Chen, H. & Canny, J. An Efficient Minibatch Acceptance Test for Metropolis-Hastings. *Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI)* (2017).
- 22. **Seita**, **D.**, Pokorny, F. T., Mahler, J., Kragic, D., Franklin, M., Canny, J. & Goldberg, K. Large-Scale Supervised Learning of the Grasp Robustness of Surface Patch Pairs. *IEEE International Conference on Simulation, Modeling, and Programming for Autonomous Robots (SIMPAR) (2016).*

PUBLICATIONS (WORKSHOPS)

- 23. **Seita**, **D.**, Gopal, A., Mandi, Z. & Canny, J. DCUR: Data Curriculum for Teaching via Samples with Reinforcement Learning. *NeurIPS Workshop on Offline Reinforcement Learning* (2021).
- 24. **Seita**, **D.**, Kerr, J., Canny, J. & Goldberg, K. Initial Results on Grasping and Lifting Physical Deformable Bags with a Bimanual Robot. *IROS Workshop on Deformable Object Manipulation* (2021).
- 25. **Seita**, **D.**, Tang, C., Rao, R., Chan, D., Zhao, M. & Canny, J. ZPD Teaching Strategies for Deep Reinforcement Learning from Demonstrations. *Deep Reinforcement Learning Workshop*, *NeurIPS* (2019).

TEACHING AT USC

Deep Learning for Robotic Manipulation (CS 699) Introduction to Robotics (CS 545) Deep Learning for Robotic Manipulation (CS 699) Fall 2024 Spring 2024 Fall 2023

TEACHING AND GUEST LECTURES (PRIOR TO USC)

Guest lecture on deep Q-learning, Statistical Techniques for Robotics (CMU, CS 16-831), Prof. David Held
Guest lecture on deep RL (National University of Singapore, CS5260), Prof. Yang You
Guest lecture on imitation learning, Deep Reinforcement Learning (CMU, CS 10-703), Prof. Katerina Fragkiadaki
Guest lecture on policy gradients, Statistical Techniques for Robotics (CMU, CS 16-831), Prof. David Held
Fall 2021
TA for Designing, Visualizing, & Understanding Deep Neural Networks (Berkeley, CS 182/282A), Prof. John Canny
TA for Designing, Visualizing, & Understanding Deep Neural Networks (Berkeley, CS 182/282A), Prof. John Canny
Fall 2016

MENTORING

Name	Institution	Status	Years	Next
Charlene Yuen	USC	MS CS	2023-	
Kriti Asjia	USC	MS CS	2023-	
Karan Owalekar	USC	MS CS	2023-	
Enyu Zhao	USC	MS CS	2023-	
Anupam Patil	USC	MS CS	2023-	
Vedant Raval	USC	MS CS	2023-	
Dhanush Penmetsa	USC	MS ECE	2023-	
Yuhai Wang	USC	MS Analytics	2023-	
Hao Jiang	USC	Undergrad	2023-	
Emily K. Zhu	USC	Undergrad	2023-	
Qian (Peter) Wang	USC	Undergrad	2023-2024	
Ce (Chris) Wang	USC	Visitor	2023-2024	
Mansi Agarwal	CMU	MS Robotics	2023	Amazon
Sashank Tirumala	CMU	MS Robotics	2021-2023	AIM Intelligent Machines
Sarthak Shetty	CMU	MS MechEng	2021-2023	Path Robotics
Edward Li	CMU	Undergrad	2021-2023	
Baiyu Shi	UC Berkeley	Undergrad	2022-2023	Stanford ME PhD
Vincent Lim	UC Berkeley	Undergrad	2021-2022	
Zhao Mandi	UC Berkeley	Undergrad	2019-2021	Stanford CS PhD
Abhinav Gopal	UC Berkeley	Undergrad/MS	2020-2021	Berkeley EECS MS $ ightarrow$ Rubbrband
Harry Zhang	UC Berkeley	Undergrad	2020-2021	CMU MS Robotics \rightarrow MIT AA/Stat PhD
Jonathan Wang	UC Berkeley	Undergrad	2020-2021	Quant Research at DRW
Samuel Paradis	UC Berkeley	Undergrad/MS	2019-2021	Google
Edward Cen	UC Berkeley	Undergrad	2019	Hudson River Trading
Aditya Ganapathi	UC Berkeley	Undergrad	2019-2021	Berkeley EECS MS $ ightarrow$ Grabango
Ryan Hoque	UC Berkeley	Undergrad/MS	2018-2020	Berkeley EECS PhD

COMMITTEES FOR OTHER STUDENTS

Name	Institution	Committee	Dates
David Blanco Mulero	Aalto University	PhD Reviewer	2023-2024
Gautam Salhotra	USC	PhD Defense	12/2023
Hejia Zhang	USC	PhD Proposal	11/2023
Jeremy Morgan	USC	Qualifying Exam	11/2023

RESEARCH TALKS

Representations in Robot Manipulation: Learning to Manipulate Ropes, Fabrics, Bags, Liquids, and Plants			
University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign	April 2023		
University of Toronto	April 2023		
University of Southern California	April 2023		
Princeton University	April 2023		
Northeastern University	March 2023		
Duke University	March 2023		
University of Wisconsin – Madison	March 2023		
New York University	March 2023		

Columbia University	March 2023
University of Washington	Nov. 2022
University of Michigan	Nov. 2022
Cornell University	Oct. 2022
Carnegie Mellon University	Sept. 2022
Recent Progress in Deformable Object Manipulation	
Carnegie Mellon University, lab of Prof. Wenzhen Yuan	May 2022
Carnegie Mellon University, lab of Prof. Zackory Erickson	Jan. 2022
Deformable Object Manipulation with Model-Free, Model-Based, and Transporter Network Methods	
University of California, Berkeley, BAIR Seminar	April 2021
Carnegie Mellon University, lab of Prof. David Held	April 2021
Stanford University, multiple labs	April 2021
Williams College, Colloquium	April 2021
University of Toronto, AI in Robotics Seminar	March 2021
Siemens Corporation	Feb. 2021
Object- and Action-Centric Learning	
NeurIPS 2020 Robot Learning Workshop (invited to assist Research Scientist Pete Florence).	Dec. 2020

OTHER TALKS AND OUTREACH

- (04/2022) Panelist speaker for a Exploring Computing and Information Sciences/Technology for Deaf and Hard-of-Hearing, hosted by the University of Washington and Gallaudet University.
- (02/2021) Panelist speaker for a "Society, Robots and Us" conversation, on people with disabilities and robots.
- (02/2021) Panelist speaker for Explore Computer Science Research Workshop, hosted by Gallaudet University.
- (01/2021) Panelist speaker for the OurCS@UW+AccessComputing discussion on managing disability access in academia/work.

ACADEMIC SERVICE

- Registration Co-Chair for RSS 2024.
- Inclusion Co-Chair for CoRL 2022 and CoRL 2023.
- Organizing Committee for RSS Pioneers 2023.
- Associate Editor: IROS 2022 and IROS 2023.
- Workshop Co-Organizer: one of the primary organizers for the Workshop on Representing and Manipulating Deformable Objects at ICRA 2022 and ICRA 2023.
- Paper Reviewing: in the interest of full disclosure, this webpage has a complete list of my paper reviewing duties, with paper venues and the number of reviewed papers per year, for workshops, conferences, and journals.
- (09/2021 to 12/2021, 10/2022) Mentor for the CMU AI Mentoring Program.
- (06/2017 to 08/2021) Primary maintainer for the Berkeley Al Research Blog; responsible for advertising and soliciting posts.
- (12/2019 and 12/2020) Assisted EECS faculty with reviewing PhD applications to Berkeley AI Research.
- (09/2018 to 12/2018) Mentor for the Berkeley Al Mentoring Program.
- (09/2016 to 10/2017) Served as the Computer Science Graduate Student Association Industrial Liaison, raised \$20,000.

AWARDS AND HONORS

Best Industrial Robotics Research for Applications Finalist at IROS 2023.	2023
Best Paper Award at IROS 2022 ROMADO-SI Workshop.	2022
Invited to attend RSS Pioneers.	2022
Eugene L. Lawler Prize. (\$2000)	2019
Honorable Mention, Best Student Paper Award at UAI 2017. (\$500)	2017
Graduate Fellowships for STEM Diversity (GFSD) Fellowship, a 6-year fellowship for research. (\$120,000)	2015-2021
Honorable Mention, NSF Graduate Research Fellowship.	2015
Berkeley Fellowship, a 2-year fellowship awarded to selected incoming UC Berkeley students. (\$59,000)	2014-2016
Lucille B. Abt Scholarship, award by the AG Bell Association for the Deaf and Hard of Hearing. (\$7,500)	2014

WORK EXPERIENCE (PRIOR TO FINISHING PHD)

Research Intern May 2020 — Sept 2020

Google

New York City, NY (Virtual)

• Worked in the Google AI robotics team, hosted by Research Scientist Andy Zeng. My project was on robot manipulation using simulators and machine learning for deformable object manipulation.

Research Intern May 2016 — Aug 2016

National Security Agency

Laurel, MD

• Worked on a research project to utilize reinforcement learning agents for the problem of computer network defense.

Consultant May 2015 — Aug 2015

Rochester Institute of Technology

Rochester, NY (Virtual)

• Worked as a consultant for an REU at RIT which focused on technology accessibility research for people with disabilities, and provided feedback on students' research progress. REU supervisor: Prof. Raja Kushalnagar.

OTHER INFORMATION

- Passed my one hour qualifying oral exam (04/2018), to become officially a "PhD candidate." Committee members: John Canny, Ken Goldberg, Sergey Levine, and Masayoshi Tomizuka.
- Achieved second highest score of 8.25/10, out of 12 Ph.D. students taking the Berkeley AI preliminary oral exams (08/2015).
- Born deaf, can speak in English and am fluent in American Sign Language.